Guide to the Chuck Stone Papers, 1931-2007 and undated RL.01259
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject Files Series, 1941-2005 and undated, bulk 1968-2005, 30 boxes
  - Roger Peck case, 1987-1990 (Box 65)
  - Philadelphia Daily News (Box 50)
    - Monitoring, 1981-1984 (Box 50)
    - Newspaper guild, 1977 (Box 50)
    - RFD's, 1981-1982 (Box 50)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer libel suit, 1988 and 1993 (Box 50)
  - Plagiarism, 1993 (Box 50)
  - PM racism; or the racially schizophrenic Daily News, 1988 (Box 50)
  - Plessy, 1996 (Box 50)
  - Poitier, Sidney, 1998 and 2003 (Box 50)
  - Police brutality, 1991 (Box 50)
  - Political correctness, 1987-2002 and undated, 2 folders (Box 50)
  - Polls, 1999 and 2004 (Box 50)
  - Poverty, 1993 (Box 50)
  - Powell IV, Adam Clayton, 1994 (Box 50)
  - Powell, Colin, 1991-1995 (Box 50)
  - Power, undated (Box 50)
  - Presidential election, 1988 (Box 51)
  - Proposal for establishment of John Hope Franklin Academy (Box 65)
  - Prostitution, 1993 (Box 51)
  - Pulitzer prize, 1985 (Box 51)
  - Quarterman, Ola Mae, 1997 (Box 51)
  - Quill, 1985, 1999 and undated (Box 51)
  - Quotations, 1988 and 1995 (Box 51)
  - Race and admissions, 1995, 1998 and 2001 (Box 51)
  - Race and the media, 1962-1968, 1984-1985, 1995 and 1999 (Box 51)
  - Racial diversity in the media, 1972, 1979 and 1990-1992 (Box 51)
  - Racial divide/racial cohesion, 1998 (Box 51)
  - Racial divisions, 1992 and 1994 (Box 51)
  - Racism and journalism, 1983-1993, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Racism and the first amendment, 1991 and 1992 (Box 51)
  - Rape and the media, 1991-1993 (Box 51)
  - Rape victims, 1991-1992 (Box 51)
  - Religious legislative bodies, 1991, 1993 and 2000 (Box 51)
  - Religious right, 1993-1995 (Box 52)
  - Renaissance paper, undated (Box 52)
  - Rendell, Ed--mayoral campaign, 1987 (Box 52)
  - Rent-a-Negro, 1984-1990 and undated (Box 52)
  - Reparations, 1956 and 2001 (Box 52)
  - Reporter's decalogue, 1992 and undated (Box 52)
  - Robinson, Jackie, 1997 (Box 52)
  - Russia, 2000-2001 and undated (Box 52)
  - Sapien Society, 1991 (Box 52)
  - Segregation, 1991 (Box 52)
  - SERVE, 1998 and undated (Box 52)
  - Sexual harassment, 1991-1993 and undated (Box 52)
  - Shumaker, Jim, 1991 and 1997-2001 (Box 52)
  - Simpson, O.J., 1994-1995 (Box 52)
  - Sins of the media, 1983-1998 (Box 52)
  - Sixth amendment, 1986-1994 and undated (Box 52)
  - Small town parochialism?, 1993 (Box 52)
  - Smith, Dean, 1990-1997 (Box 52)
  - South (elections), 1996 (Box 53)
  - South Africa, 1989-2002 and undated (Box 53)
  - South Park, 1999 (Box 53)
  - Southern culture, 1991-1993, 1997 and undated (Box 53)
  - Speaking engagements (Box 65)
  - Standardized testing (Box 53)
    - FairTest, 1989-1995 and 2002, 4 folders (Box 53)
    - The first national conference on testing in education and employment, 1971-1976 (Box 53)
    - S.A.T.s, 1971-1993 and undated (Box 54)
    - Test bias, 1968-1971, 4 folders (Box 54)
  - Statistics, 1969, 1972 and 1984-1993 (Box 54)
  - Stone, Chuck (Box 54)
    - Awards, 1974-2005 (Box 54)
    - Oversize Awards, 1974-2005 (Box 63)
    - Diplomas, 1948-1999 (Box 54)
    - Oversize Diplomas, 1948-1999 (Box 63)
    - Honors and awards (Box 64)
    - Early Stone, 1941-1965 and undated (Box 54)
    - Programs and posters, 1965-2005, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Resumes I have known, 1958-1963 and 1979-2000, 2 folders (Box 55)
  - Stone, Krishna, 1994 (Box 55)
  - Stone, Sonja Hayes, undated (Box 55)
  - Student-faculty sex, 1993 (Box 55)
  - Stutterers, 2002 (Box 55)
  - Style transparencies, 1984-2002 and undated (Box 55)
  - Style and substance, 1988-1996 and undated (Box 55)
  - Suarez, Xavier, 1987 (Box 55)
  - Suicide, 1994 and undated (Box 55)
  - Supreme court, 1991-2003 and undated (Box 55)
  - Survey on third party agreements, 1985 (Box 55)
  - Teaching and learning, 2001 (Box 55)
  - Technology vs. the liberal arts, 2001 (Box 55)
  - Ten favorite books, undated (Box 55)
  - Thomas, Clarence, 1995 (Box 55)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award, 2001 (Box 55)
  - Thoroughbred thirty, 1998 (Box 55)
  - Till, Emmett, 1997-1999 and undated (Box 55)
  - Transparencies, 1961-1963 and 1987-2000 (Box 55)
  - Travel ephemera, Liberia and Gaza, 1960s (Box 65)
  - Triads, 1985-1993 (Box 55)
  - Triangle Association of Black Communicators, 1993 (Box 55)
  - Twenty-something, 1990 (Box 55)
  - Tyson, Timothy B., undated (Box 55)
  - UNC (Box 56)
    - Advising, 2000 (Box 56)
    - African American Experience, 1997-1998 (Box 56)
    - Black Culture Center, 1992-1998, 3 folders (Box 56)
    - Black faculty/staff, 1996 and undated (Box 56)
    - Black faculty/staff caucus, 1991-1997, 2 folders (Box 56)
    - Black faculty staff caucus, 1992-1998 (Box 65)
    - Black issues forum, 2001 (Box 56)
    - Board of Visitors, 1997 (Box 56)
    - Bridges, 2001 (Box 56)
    - Buildings names, 1999 (Box 56)
    - Carolina Club, 2001 (Box 56)
    - Carroll Hall, 1999-2000 (Box 56)
    - Chancellor's task force, 1997 (Box 56)
    - Dean's search, 2005 (Box 56)
    - Daily Tar Heel, 2001 and undated (Box 56)
    - Daily Tar Heel meeting, 2002 (Box 56)
    - Faculty retreat on the undergraduate journalism curriculum, 1993 (Box 57)
    - The graduate school, 1993 (Box 57)
    - Journalism, 1991 and 2000 (Box 57)
    - School of Journalism (Box 65)
    - Minority presence, 1991-1992 (Box 57)
    - Rainbow Institute, 1991-1992 (Box 57)
    - Sheldon professorship, 2002 (Box 57)
    - Slavic and Eurasian department, 2000 (Box 57)
    - Street signs, 1997 (Box 57)
    - Student organizations, 2000 (Box 57)
    - Zhao, Xinshu, 1990-1996 (Box 57)
    - Zhao, Xinshu, research examples, 1994-1995 (Box 57)
  - Unsung heroes, 2001-2003 and undated (Box 57)
  - U.S. House of Representatives, undated (Box 57)
  - U.S.A. creed, undated (Box 57)
  - Victimizers, victims, and victimhood, 2000 (Box 57)
  - War, 1956 (Box 57)
  - Water, 2001 (Box 57)
  - Wesleyan, 2000 (Box 57)
  - Wesleyan reunion, 1948, 1983 and 1993 (Box 57)
  - West, Cornel, 1993 (Box 57)
  - West Philadelphia--Chamber of Commerce, 1982 (Box 57)
  - What newspaper d'you read?, 1980-1991 (Box 57)
  - White antagonists, 1990 and undated (Box 57)
  - White insults of Blacks, 1994 and undated (Box 57)
  - White males, 1998-1999 (Box 57)
  - Williams, Robin, undated (Box 57)
  - Wilmington riots, 2000-2002 (Box 57)
  - Women, 1988-2002 and undated, 2 folders (Box 58)
  - Women in journalism, 1984-1991 and 2003, 2 folders (Box 59)
  - Writing without bias, 1990-2002 (Box 59)
- Teaching Materials Series, 1969-2005 and undated, bulk 1990-2005, 1 box
  Contains documents Stone created or collected relating to his teaching career at the University of Delaware and the University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill. It is made up of syllabi, exams, assignments, and notes on pedagogy and academic subject areas related to journalism. The majority of the series deals with his course on censorship, which he developed at Delaware and refined while at UNC.
  - Assignments, 1983 and undated (Box 60)
  - Black politics course, 1969 (Box 60)
  - Critical thinking, 2000-2002 and undated (Box 60)
  - Encyclopedia articles comparison, undated (Box 60)
  - Exams, 1996-2005 (Box 60)
  - Final paper titles, undated (Box 60)
  - Final papers and bibliography, 1992 and undated (Box 60)
  - Notes on types of news writing, undated (Box 60)
  - Other syllabi, 1990-1991, 1997 (Box 60)
  - Specialized reporting syllabus, 1992 (Box 60)
  - Student surveys, 1999-2000 (Box 60)
  - Syllabi, 1995-2001 and undated (Box 60)
  - Teaching, 1985, 2001 (Box 60)
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1940-2006; 2 boxes
  Twelve VHS videotapes and six audiocassettes containing interviews with Stone and including a documentary on Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., from 1977. Contains black-and-white and color photographs of Stone, family members, friends, and colleagues, including a number of photographs of Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. Among the more notable figures appearing with Stone in photographs here are Malcolm X, Léopold Senghor, Nelson Rockefeller, Jesse Jackson, Henry Kissinger, Walter Mondale, John Glenn, and Dick Gregory. Also to be found here are postcards collected during a trip to India, and several press passes and identification badges.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Digital video and audio use copies are available for most of the items. The VHS and audiocassette originals are closed to use.
  - Video, 1977-2006
    - Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., an autobiographical documentary, 1977; 0:58:47
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0005)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0005.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0005.mp4)
    - Chuck Stone interview with Gil Noble, 1991-02-11; 1:18:45
      - Original videocassette, copy 1 (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0004)
      - Digital video preservation file, copy 1 (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0004.mkv)
      - Digital video access file, copy 1 (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0004.mp4)
      - Original videocassette, copy 2 (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0008)
      - Digital video preservation file, copy 2 (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0008.mkv)
      - Digital video access file, copy 2 (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0008.mp4)
    - WPVI-TV, Visions, Chuck Stone, 1991-09-15; 0:08:10
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0012)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0012.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0012.mp4)
    - NC Now Interview, Chuck Stone, 1994-10-27; 0:05:48
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0011)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0011.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0011.mp4)
    - Green Honors Lecture Series/ JOUR, Dr. Chuck Stone, Journalism's Crisis of Credibility, Texas Christian University, 1997-03-11; 1:08:52
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0010)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0010.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0010.mp4)
    - Charles Stone, Today (NBC), Regis and Kathy (CBS), 2000-03-16; 2:00:11
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0006)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0006.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0006.mp4)
    - Frontline, American Porn, 2002-02-07; 0:55:21
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0003)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0003.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0003.mp4)
    - NC Bookwatch, Chuck Stone, 2004-06-08; 0:28:41
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0007)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0007.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0007.mp4)
    - Up to the Minute, Chuck Stone interview, 2006-01-16; 0:06:45
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0009)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0009.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0009.mp4)
    - Sample edit, Chuck Stone, undated; 2:02:58
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0001)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0001.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0001.mp4)
    - News at 11 (TV), undated; 1:39:06
      - Original videocassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01259-VHS-0002)
      - Digital video preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0002.mkv)
      - Digital video access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0001, Video-file RL01259-VHS-0002.mp4)
  - Audio, 1984-1995
    - The Final Call, a message by minister Louis Farrakhan. "The Aim of True Religion!" Wheat Street Baptist Church, Atlanta, GA, 1984-09-23; 0:24:09
      - Original audiocassette (Box 67, Audio-cassette RL01259-CS-0004)
      - Digital audio preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0004_001.wav)
      - Digital audio access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0004_001.mp3)
      - Digital audio preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0004_002.wav)
      - Digital audio access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0004_002.mp3)
    - Media Breakfast, Vernon Jarrett and Chuck Stone, 1986-08-06; 0:57:22
      - Original audiocassette (Box 67, Audio-cassette RL01259-CS-0002)
      - Digital audio preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0002_001.wav)
      - Digital audio access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0002_001.mp3)
      - Digital audio preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0002_002.wav)
      - Digital audio access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0002_002.mp3)
    - Robyn Booker Young, Mt. Zion Baptist Church, 1988-09-23
      - Original audiocassette (Box 67, Audio-cassette RL01259-CS-0005)
    - Robyn at Grace, 1988-11-06
      - Original audiocassette (Box 67, Audio-cassette RL01259-CS-0006)
    - Mark Scott with Chuck Stone, 1995-10-19; 0:35:50
      - Original audiocassette (Box 67, Audio-cassette RL01259-CS-0003)
      - Digital audio preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0003_001.wav)
      - Digital audio access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0003_001.mp3)
    - University Day speech by Chuck Stone, undated; 0:36:36
      - Original audiocassette (Box 67, Audio-cassette RL01259-CS-0001)
      - Digital audio preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0001_001.wav)
      - Digital audio access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0001_001.mp3)
      - Digital audio preservation file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0001_002.wav)
      - Digital audio access file (Digital-materials RL01259-SET-0002, Audio-file RL01259-CS-0001_002.mp3)
  - Photographs (Box 61)
    - Autographed photo, undated, 1 photograph (Box 61)
    - Boycott of the Philadelphia Daily News and various others with Stone, 1990 and undated, 5 photographs (Box 61)
    - Collage of former Chicago Defender editors, undated, 1 item (Box 61)
    - Commencement photos and Stone interview subjects, 1976, 1985 and undated, 5 items (Box 61)
    - Congressional photos
      - Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., circa 1960s, 19 items (Box 61)
      - Adam Clayton Powell, Jr., Stone with Charlie Parker, CARE, hostages photos, circa 1960-1980 and undated, 23 items (Box 61)
      - Adam Clayton Powell, Jr. with Stone, undated, 3 photographs (Box 61)
    - Double Dutch contest, Philadelphia, 1981, 1 photograph (Box 61)
    - 80th birthday celebration, 2004, 33 photographs (Box 61)
    - Group photo with Stone, 1982, 1 photograph (Box 61)
    - Lecturing in Russia, 2000, 6 photographs (Box 61)
    - Commencement photos and Stone interview subjects, 1976, 1985 and undated, 5 items (Box 61)
    - Personal photos
      - Childhood and family, circa 1940s-1960s and undated, 19 items, 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Oversize photographs (Box 63)
      - Krishna, Allegra, and Charles Stone III, 1992, 1 photograph (Box 61)
      - Stone in conversation with unidentified figures, 1983, 2 photographs (Box 61)
    - Pete Dexter Fan Club photo, circa 1970s, 1 photograph (Box 61)
    - Philadelphia Daily News office, undated, 2 photographs (Box 61)
    - Press release photos and assorted party photos, 1975, 2003, 2005 and undated, 6 items (Box 61)
    - Russians' campus tour, 1994, 1 photograph (Box 61)
    - Shumaker, Jim, undated, 1 photograph (Box 61)
    - Somalian embassy reception, 1962, 1 photograph (Box 61)
    - Stone with various significant figures, circa 1956-1992, 104 items, 4 folders (Box 61A)
    - Surrenders, office photos, Stone on location, 1970s and undated, 32 items (Box 61A)
    - Teaching photos, circa 1971-1991, 6 photographs (Box 61A)
    - Trip to Mozambique, 2000, 11 photographs (Box 61A)
    - Tuskegee airmen and Stone family photo, circa 1970s and undated, 2 photocopies (Box 61A)
    - UNC-Chapel Hill faculty photo, 2002, 1 photograph (Box 61A)
    - Various Chuck Stone photos, circa 1960s-2000, 1-2 folders; 2 folders (Box 61A)
    - Various Chuck Stone photos, circa 1960s-2000 (Box 62)
    - Various photos, without Stone (Box 62)
    - Wesleyan reunion, 1968, 1983, 3 photographs (Box 62)
  - Postcards from trip to Bombay, undated (Box 62)
  - Press passes and identification badges, 1964 and undated (Box 62)
  - "Remove Rizzo" pin, undated (Box 62)
- Unprocessed Addition (2009-0009), 1963-2005, 2 folders
  Comprises primarily (folder 1) photographs, but also contains a few letters, clippings, awards, and a dvd-r. The original DVD-R (folder 2) is closed to patron use; however, the information on the disk has been migrated to the electronic records server.